56NT 7/12/15
Page 1 of 3

SUE FEI

Email: sue.fei9@gmail.com Phone: 647-898-6692

HIGHLIGHTS

• 10+ years of experience in all aspects of freight forwarding for Ocean & Air freight

- Proficient at Microsoft Office (Excel, Word and Outlook), Internet etc..
- Strong time management and organizational skills with the ability to multi-task, handle large volume of work and meet tight deadlines
- Strong negotiating skills with carrier, vendor and customs brokers, truck agency
- Solid knowledge of transportation procedures and policies as well as International ocean/air transportation documentation requirements
- Strong decision making skills

- a and

- Excellent customer services skills with the ability to solve issue effectively
- Strong Strategic and analytical skills
- Extremely productive in a high volume and high stress environment
- Detailed and accuracy oriented
- Understanding of incotems
- Experience with SAP and ERP
- Experience with HS tariff classification, valuations of commodities and calculation of duty and taxes
- Knowledge of Reefer & D.G cargo procedure
- Capable of working both independently and as part of a team

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Import specialist II

Ceva Logistics

Jan 2015 - Up to now

- Handling more than 500 TUES shipments from worldwide to Toronto
- Updating cargo tracking in company system
- Updating selling rate and buying rate for each cargo
- Providing cargo status and details to customer and relative department
- Sending shipping instruction to overseas
- Booking delivery appointment for each customer.
- Handling and claiming for damaged cargo
- Handling for direct truck from Vancouver terminal to Toronto.

Logistics Manager

Canaan Transport Group Inc.

OCT 2012 to Jan 2015

Cell: 647-898-6692

- Handling shipments for goods being imported into or exported out of Canada
- Effectively and Efficiently carry out the processing of such files on a daily basis and with a 99% accuracy rate
- Preparing pre-arrival notices, pre-alerts, ocean bills of lading, invoices and any other documents via FORWARDERLOGIC, Microsoft Office Suite, Simply Accounting, or any other computer program
- Communicating with customers, suppliers, carriers or agents via e-mail, telephone, fax, or in person with little or no supervision
- Identifying key problems and concerns and bringing them to the attention of the President on a timely basis
- collect all monies owing without fail, including issuing correct invoices and ensuring monies are collected prior to goods release
- Issuing cheques to cover any outstanding liabilities regarding shipments Releasing goods to be released to customers
- Reducing the risk of liability for cargo that is imported into Canada by ensuring all proper procedures are followed for each file from cradle to grave
- Recording all file information in the manner as specified by management from time to time
- Ensuring all files are prioritized properly based on arrival dates and urgency
- Checking on the internet for cargo arrival via various websites such as the carriers or railroads' websites

Import Coordinator

Shipco Transport Inc.

June2011 to Oct2012

- Follow up with customers to resolve inquires
- Prepare, route, and cut sea bills and manifests
- Correct billings and issue debit and credit memos for customers
- Arrange for pick up and movement of freight to gateways
- Tracking and tracing the shipment
- Expedite inbound import traffic to facilitate customs clearance
- Initiate and maintain customer master profiles in order to have correct information on hand in order to offer consistent service.
- Maintain close liaison with the Canada Customs Service and for various specialized Canada Customs clearance requirements.
- Key in Canada Customs entry line items into the Import Computer System and submit entry to customs.
- Communicating information and instructions to/from vendors.
- Researching and resolving operational problems.
- Review all documents, contact all first-time customers, perform credit checks, and handle other tasks as needed.

Cell: 647-898-6692

Solution claim case and risk & cost control management

Administrative Assistant for Senior Support Group (Volunteer) **Newcomer Centre of Peel (NCP)**

Mar. 2011 - Jun 2011

LCL Department Manager Helka Express international Co. Shanghai

July 2007- March 2011

- Initiated Helka's weekly consolidation services from Shanghai to America
- Progressively increased free-hand cargo for consolidation to destinations in USA and Canada
- Expanded the LCL business through advertising, sales calls, visits and good customer service
- Managed operations of the LCL department on a day-to-day basis
- Generated and reviewed reports on volumes, outstanding accounts, profits and incidents etc.
- Conducted weekly meetings of the department
- Negotiated freight rates with carriers for freight and monitored tariff rates on a daily basis
- Prepared and submitted price quotes for customer
- Functioned as cost & risk control manager
- Trained the new recruits and carried out programs to update the staff periodically

Pan Asia Line Sea Export Supervisor Schenker International Ltd. Shanghai

July 1996 - July 2007

- Led teams to handle over 800 TEUs of FCLs and consolidated over 200 TEUs of LCLs per month
- Managed cargo destined to over 30 countries in North & South America, Asia, and Europe
- Prepared shipping and bank documents for imports and exports by all modes of transportation
- Entered remote inbound outbound documents (EDI)
- Developed Maintenance and operating standards for export process
- Canvassed and retained large accounts such as Philips, BASF, ABS, Watson
- Developed a strong relationship with customers, partners, overseas offices and colleagues
- Investigated and solved any customer concerns and complaints
- Arranged payments to vendors, invoiced clients and overseas offices
- Followed up outstanding accounts with clients
- Processing merchandise fees for all air and ocean export shipments

EDUCATION

CITT course

Sheridan College

Sept 2012 - June.2013

Masters, Major in New Medium

Inter American University

Sept. 2002 - June 2004

Bachelor of Science, Major in English for science & Technology

East of China University of Chemical Technology

Sept. 1989 - June 1992

Reference available upon request

SUE. FEI 9@ GMAIL. COM 647-898-6692

sue fei

Import Specialist at CEVA Logistics

Summary

10+ years of experience in all aspects of freight forwarding for Ocean & Air freight # Proficient at Microsoft Office (Excel, Word and Outlook), Internet etc.. # Strong time management and organizational skills with the ability to multi-task, handle large volume of work and meet tight deadlines # Strong negotiating skills with carrier, vendor and customs brokers, truck agency # Solid knowledge of transportation procedures and policies as well as International ocean/air transportation documentation requirements # Strong decision making skills # Excellent customer services skills with the ability to solve issue effectively # Strong Strategic and analytical skills # Extremely productive in a high volume and high stress environment # Detailed and accuracy oriented # Understanding of incotems # Experience with SAP and ERP # Experience with HS tariff classification, valuations of commodities and calculation of duty and taxes # Knowledge of Reefer & D.G cargo procedure # Capable of working both independently and as part of a team

Experience

Import Specialist at CEVA Logistics

January 2015 - Present (10 months)

Handling more than 500 TUES shipments from worldwide to Toronto # Updating cargo tracking in company system # Updating selling rate and buying rate for each cargo # Providing cargo status and details to customer and relative department # Sending shipping instruction to overseas # Booking delivery appointment for each customer. # Handling and claiming for damaged cargo # Handling for direct truck from Vancouver terminal to Toronto.

Logistics coordinator at Canaan Transport Group Inc.

February 2013 - Present (2 years 9 months)

Handling shipments for goods being imported into or exported out of Canada but primarily via Toronto and Montreal and Vancouver # Effectively and Efficiently carry out the processing of such files on a daily basis and with a 99% accuracy rate o Preparing pre#arrival notices, pre#alerts, ocean bills of lading, invoices and any other documents via FORWARDERLOGIC, Microsoft Office Suite, Simply Accounting, or any other computer program o Communicating with customers, suppliers, carriers or agents via e#mail, telephone, fax, or in person with little or no supervision o Identifying key problems and concerns and bringing them to the attention of the President on a timely basis o Collect all monies owing without fail, including issuing correct invoices and ensuring monies are collected prior to goods release o Issuing cheques to cover any outstanding liabilities regarding the shipments o Releasing or causing goods to be released to customers o Reducing the risk of liability for cargo that is imported into Canada by ensuring all proper procedures are followed for each file from cradle to grave o Recording all file information in the manner as specified by

customer concerns and complaints # Arranged payments to vendors, invoiced clients and overseas offices # Followed up outstanding accounts with clients # Processing merchandise fees for all air and ocean export shipments

Volunteer Experience

Admin assistant at NCP

April 2011 - June 2011 (3 months)

Organization for Senior program, made the attendance report, Art and health program

Courses

MASTER, MULTI MEDIA

INTER-AMERICAN UNIVERSITY

TRANSPORTATION

CITT

Languages

Mandrain

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

Freight Forwarding

Shipping

Customs Clearance

Import

Logistics Management

Import/Export

Customs

International Trade

3PL

International Logistics

OCEAN FREIGHT FORWARDING

Transportation Management

WAREHOUSE TRANSPORATION

EXPORT SUPPLY CHAIN

Supply Chain Management

SHIPPING OPERATION MANAGEMENT

Key Account Management

Continuous Improvement

Ocean Freight

Customs Regulations

Operations Management

sue fei

Import Specialist at CEVA Logistics



2 people have recommended sue

"Sue is a very nice friend, always willing to help or support others in need. Working with Sue was a good thing, very responsive, cooperative, professional and can tackle many unexpected issues in a efficient way. Sue persues a simple and healthy lifestyle."

— Peng Hock T., was a consultant or contractor to sue at Shipco Transport

"For me, Sue is a very good and reliable friend and colleague. She is very nice and friendly, always willing to help or support others in need. Working with Sue is a happy thing, as she is quite responsible, cooperative, professional, and can tackle many unexpected issues in a efficient way. Also, in life, Sue persues a simple and healthy lifestyle. She quite understands how to keep a balance in her life and work."

— Qi Shi, worked with sue at DB Schenker

Contact sue on LinkedIn